STEVAN BOGOSAVLJEVIC

Podgorica, Montenegro • +38267125552 • stevanbogosavljevic@gmail.com

stevyhacker.github.io



Solidity Engineer

Summary

I am a Software Engineer from Podgorica, Montenegro (CET) with 6+ years of software development experience.

At the start of 2021, I moved on from my mobile app development career to web3. I have been following crypto development and especially the Ethereum ecosystem since 2017. DeFi and NFTs got me very interested and I decided to go all-in as a smart contract engineer.

I have a year of experience with Solidity, using Hardhat, ethers.js, and also have some frontend dev experience, mostly React/Typescript.

For most of my web2 career, I have been working on Android mobile app development with Kotlin/Java where I learned good software engineering practices. I participated in many hackathons, workshops, contests, and I am always striving to improve my technical skills and broaden my knowledge.

I mentored and taught Android development in two beginner courses and have led, and managed a mobile development team as well.

Work History

June 2021 - Present Solidity Engineer

MVP Workshop

Development of contracts for various NFT related projects.

Developed contracts for an NFT Liquidity protocol on Polygon with Sushiswap integration and Rarible Royalty protocol implementation.

Researching and experimenting on new DeFi/NFT trends to filter potential products for further development.

Sep 2020 - Oct 2021 Android Engineer

Infinum

Working in an international IT agency with an experienced Android team for large-scale enterprise clients, mobile banking, telecom self-care apps, etc.

Sep 2019 - Sep 2020 Mobile Development Lead

Amplitudo

Started as a Senior Android Developer and was promoted to Mobile development teamlead from November 2019 onwards.

Taught a 6 month Android course for beginner programmers.

Dec 2018 - Aug 2019 Android developer

GSS Media

Worked on Android and Android TV apps for a live TV/Video on demand platform.

Oct 2018 - Jun 2019 Android developer

Sportamix

App development for a youth sports networking platform.

Oct 2017 - Oct 2018 Android developer

SAFE Group

I worked remotely for a health tech startup from Los Angeles.

Aug 2016 - Oct 2018 Android & Fire TV developer

GTV Corp

Worked on white label video streaming Android applications and Android TV and Fire TV apps. Remote position for a startup from the USA.

Mar 2016 - Jun 2016 Android & Web developer

Codingo

I worked as a developer working on android applications as well as some basic web PHP/Laravel projects.

Oct 2014 - Present Freelance Android developer

Self-employed

I worked on various projects that come from personal references and freelance platforms. On Upwork I had some projects for blockchain apps for example.

Jun 2014 - Sep 2014 Intern Android developer

Fleka

Summer internship at Fleka, interactive design studio based in Podgorica.

Nov 2013 - Jan 2014 Volunteer Android Developer

Telenor

I volunteered at Telenor to develop an app for Telenor's SurfWisely (Surfuj Pametno) initiative to educate children about using the internet safely. The application was launched to the public in January 2014.

Education

Sep 2015 - Nov 2017 Computer Science

University of Montenegro

I studied for two years on Computer Science at the Faculty of Sciences and Mathematics in Podgorica, at the University of Montenegro until I quit to focus on work.

2011 - Present Open online courses

Udacity, Coursera, FreeCodeCamp

I have enrolled in numerous online courses and they have greatly contributed to my education. I consider them essential for learning new skills.

2011 - 2015 High school diploma

Gimnazija "Stojan Cerovic"

I finished High School in Niksic, Montenegro.

Skills

Blockchain development

I develop smart contracts in Solidity with Hardhat. I use the OpenZeppelin contract library extensively. I developed projects built on their ERC20, ERC721, and ERC1155 implementations as well as used their upgradeable contracts version.

I have developed products with Uniswap v2 protocol integrations. My contracts have tests in Typescript and I use plugins to measure gas costs for contract functions. Tenderly is my go-to tool when I have an issue with a specific smart contract state.

Java/Kotlin

I developed native apps in Java and Kotlin. I started using Kotlin in 2018 and can use these languages interchangeably in the same projects. I am also familiar with various code architectures and design patterns.

Android

I have many years of professional experience with Android SDK and various 3rd party APIs, libraries, and SDKs like Firebase, Room, RxJava, Stripe, AdMob, Leanback, Exoplayer, Google Maps, Realm, Retrofit, Parse, Facebook, Crashlytics, etc. I worked on apps for mobile phones, tablets, and smart TVs.

Design tools

I have used various UI/UX tools like Sketch, Figma, Invision, Zeplin, Adobe XD, etc.

Web3 development

I worked on implementing smart contract integrations with ethers.js and web3.js in React-based projects and I have some backend Node.js experience as well. I also used web3 modal and create-eth-app for faster project setup and easier wallet connection.

Git & Open Source

I use Git as my code version control system of choice. I am also an open-source supporter and try to contribute as much as possible to the projects I use. Check my GitHub account: https://github.com/stevyhacker

Database/SQL

I worked with SQLite databases, used Room ORM for Android. I had experience with MongoDB and Realm as NoSQL examples.

